Felipe Reis

<u>falreis.eng.br</u> <u>github.com/falreis</u> linkedin.com/in/falreis

A full-stack software developer for web and desktop environments since 2006. Extensive experience working on large-scale projects in accounting, education, and finance industries. Highly proficient in ASP.NET C#, PHP, and relational databases.

Technical Skills

Languages: ASP.NET C#/VB, C++, Java, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, Python

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL

Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, Visual Studio, Eclipse

Other: Scrum, Git/GitHub, SVN, Google Cloud, Amazon AWS, Anaconda, Jupyter, GIMP

Work Experience

<u>Prodabel</u> - Information Technology Analyst

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | May 2014 - July 2017

- Gathered and analyzed requirements to define solutions, developed and supported new accounting software,
 CASP a Brazilian standard for public accounting;
- Migrated an old accounting software to the new version (including data), developed procedures for accounting processing/closure, developed reports, allowing publish the balance sheet based on the system's data.
- Technologies used: PowerBuilder 12.5 (Desktop), PHP Zend 1.1 (Web), Oracle (Database)

<u>Ci&T Software S.A.</u> - Full Software Engineer

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | July 2013 - March 2014

- Developed and supported an educational software (academic and financial areas);
- Technologies used: Classic ASP (Web), Oracle (Database)

<u>CSI Services Ltda.</u> - System Information Developer

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | September 2012 - June 2013

- Gathered and analyzed requirements, created Scrum Backlog, defined system architecture and developed new software to manage company's printers and hardware resources (outsourced company);
- Developed a print filter for Linux Operating System, using CUPS technology, and a layer to integrate with a Java application, to block printing if the user is unauthorized.
- Technologies used: ASP.NET C# 4.0 + NHibernate (Web), MSSQL (Database), C++ (CUPS)

Squadra Ltda. - Software Analyst

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | October 2011 - June 2012

- Developed and supported a web application to buy public transportation credits;
- Developed and supported of web application of bid control and electronic trading;
- Technologies used: ASP.NET C# 3.5/4.0 + NHibernate/Spring (Web), Oracle, MSSQL, CrystalReports.

Education

PUC Minas, Brazil - Masters in Informatics
Udacity - Self Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Program
PUC Minas, Brazil - Industrial Engineering, Lato sensu post graduation
CEFET-MG, Brazil - Computer Engineering, B.S.
CEFET-MG, Brazil - Industrial Computer, Technical Level

IN PROGRESS May 2018

October 2017

December 2012

December 2005

Other Information

Language Skills - Portuguese (native), English (proficient), French (intermediary proficiency)

Business Pre-incubation Program - software development, mostly in PHP, between 2010/10 and 2011/12

Scientific Research - 5 papers, published in conferences and magazines

Detailed information and work experiences before 2012 - please visit my LinkedIn profile.